A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Education, 1994; 1998-2006
Library of Virginia
- II. Correspondence and Supporting Documentation: Assigned State Agencies, 1998-2005., Extent: 11.03 cubic feet (32 boxes). (Box 3-30)
  - Subseries II.B. Higher Education and State Agencies, 1998-2005., Extent: 9.10 cubic feet. (Box 8-29)
    - State Agencies
      - Department of Education, Summit for Education Excellence, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Department of Education, Briefing Notebooks, 7 December 2001 (part one) (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Department of Education, Briefing Notebooks, 7 December 2001 (part two) (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Department of Education, Briefing Notebooks, 7 December 2001 (part three) (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Department of Education, Briefing Notebooks, 7 December 2001 (part four) (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Department of Education, Briefing Notebooks, 7 December 2001 (part five) (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Department of Education, Briefing Notebooks, 7 December 2001 (part six) (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Department of Education, Briefing Notebooks, 7 December 2001 (part seven) (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Department of Education, 2002-2005(part one) (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Department of Education, 2002-2005 (part two) (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Department of Education, 2002-2005 (part three) (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Department of Education, 2002-2005 (part four) (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Department of Education, 2002-2005 (part five) (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Department of Education, 2002-2005 (part six) (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Department of Education, 2002-2005 (part seven) (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Department of Education, K-12, 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Department of Education, K-12, 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Department of Education, Miscellaneous, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Department of Education, Elementary and Secondary Education Act, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Frontier Culture Museum of Virginia, 2002-2005 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Gunston Hall Plantation, 1998-2005 (part one) (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Gunston Hall Plantation, 1998-2005 (part two) (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2001-2005 (part one) (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2001-2005 (part two) (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2001-2005 (part three) (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2001-2005 (part four) (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2001-2005 (part five) (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2001-2005 (part six) (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2001-2005 (part seven) (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2001-2005 (part eight) (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Library of Virginia, 2002-2005 (part one) (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Library of Virginia, 2002-2005 (part two) (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Library of Virginia, 2002-2005 (part three) (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Library of Virginia, 2002-2005 (part four) (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Library of Virginia, 2002-2005 (part five) (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Science Museum of Virginia, 2002-2005 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Belmont Bay Science Center, 2005 (part one) (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Belmont Bay Science Center, 2005 (part two) (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Virginia Commission for the Arts, 2002-2005 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 2002-2005 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Virginia School for the Deaf and the Blind, 2002-2005 (part one) (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Virginia School for the Deaf and the Blind, 2002-2005 (part two) (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Virginia School for the Deaf and the Blind, 2002-2005 (part three) (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Other
      - Center for Innovative Technology, 2002, 2004-2005 (part one) (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Center for Innovative Technology, 2002, 2004-2005 (part two) (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2005 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - National Governors Association, 2002-2005 (part one) (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - National Governors Association, 2002-2005 (part two) (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Tredegar National Civil War Center, 2002-2005 (part one) (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Tredegar National Civil War Center, 2002-2005 (part two) (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Department of Education PASS Correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 28a, Folder 1)
      - Department of Education PASS Correspondence, 2003 (Box 28a, Folder 2)
      - PASS Memorandum of Agreements, 2003 (Box 28a, Folder 3)
      - Department of Education PASS Correspondence, 2004 (Box 28a, Folder 4)
      - Department of Education PASS Correspondence, 2004 (Box 28a, Folder 5)
      - Department of Education PASS Correspondence, 2004 (Box 28a, Folder 6)
      - Department of Education PASS Correspondence, 2004 (Box 28a, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence with School Systems, Botetourt County - Greensville County (Box 28b, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with School Systems, Halifax County - New Kent County (Box 28b, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with School Systems, Newport News - Prince William County (Box 28b, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with School Systems, Prince William County - Charter Schools (Box 28b, Folder 4)
      - Hurricane Isabel, Actions taken by Education Secretariat Employees, 2003 (Box 28b, Folder 5)
      - Frontier Culture Museum, Zirkle Mill, 2004-2005 (Box 28b, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Workforce Council, 2002-2005 (part one) (Box 28b, Folder 7)
      - Virginia Workforce Council, 2002-2005 (part two) (Box 28c, Folder 1)
      - Virginia Workforce Council, 2002-2005 (part three) (Box 28c, Folder 2)
      - Virginia Workforce Council, 2002-2005 (part four) (Box 28c, Folder 3)
      - 2005 Virginia Congressional Delegation Meeting, 14 March 2005 (Box 28c, Folder 4)
      - Higher Education Issues, State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, Briefing for Governor-Elect Mark Warner, 6 December 2001 (part one) (Box 28d, Folder 1)
      - Higher Education Issues, State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, Briefing for Governor-Elect Mark Warner, 6 December 2001 (part two) (Box 28d, Folder 2)
      - Accord Between Virginia and United States Dept. of Education, Office for Civil Rights (Norfolk State University), 2001-2005 (part one) (Box 28d, Folder 3)
      - Accord Between Virginia and United States Dept. of Education, Office for Civil Rights (Norfolk State University), 2001-2005 (part two) (Box 28d, Folder 4)
      - Accord Between Virginia and United States Dept. of Education, Office for Civil Rights (Norfolk State University), 2001-2005 (part three) (Box 28d, Folder 5)
      - Accord Between Virginia and United States Dept. of Education, Office for Civil Rights (Norfolk State University), 2001-2005 (part four) (Box 28d, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Business-Education Partnership, 2002-2003 (part one) (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Virginia Business-Education Partnership, 2002-2003 (part two) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Subseries II.C. Continuity of Operations Planning (COOP), 2003-2005., Extent: 1 folder. (Box 29)
    This subseries is housed in 1 folder and is arranged alphabetically by agency. Records primarily contain letters from agency heads certifying that they have a viable COOP. A copy of the Continuity of Operations Plan is not included.
    - Continuity of Operations Planning, 2003-2005 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.D. Small, Women-owned and Minority Businesses (SWAM), 2003-2005., Extent: 6 folders. (Box 29-30)
    This subseries is housed in 6 folders and is arranged alphabetically by agency. Records include quarterly SWAM totals for the first quarter of fiscal year 2006 for education agencies. Also included is a copy of each agency's Supplier Diversity Model Program as required by Governor Warner's Executive Order 29, Equal Opportunity in State Procurement, issued on 2 July 2002.
    - SWAM Quarterly Totals, 1Q FY 2006 (30 September 2005) (part one) (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - SWAM Quarterly Totals, 1Q FY 2006 (30 September 2005) (part two) (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - SWAM Quarterly Totals, 1Q FY 2006 (30 September 2005) (part three) (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - SWAM Quarterly Totals, 1Q FY 2006 (30 September 2005) (part four) (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Supplier Diversity Model Program, 2003 (part one) (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Supplier Diversity Model Program, 2003 (part two) (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - SWAM Analysis, 2003-2005 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- III. Constituent Correspondence, 2002-2005., Extent: 11.90 cubic feet (34 boxes). (Box 31-64)
  The Constituent Correspondence series is housed in 34 archival boxes and is arranged roughly by chronological order by last action taken. This series documents constituent correspondence received by the Office of the Secretary of Education during Governor Mark Warner's administration. This series contains correspondence from various constituents to Governor Mark W. Warner, along with a copy of Belle Wheelan's (2002-2005) or Peter Blake's (2005-2006) letter in response, and a page from the people summary database which includes the name, address, and phone number of the correspondent. Each letter in this series contains a unique tracking number assigned by the Governor's Office Constituent Services. Records are arranged by outgoing tracking number.
  Some of the notable correspondence in this series relates to the following topics: No Child Left Behind, Tuition Assistance Grant (TAG) program, education funding, Standards of Learning (SOL), budget cuts in state aid to public libraries, college tuition increases, teacher salaries, consolidating the Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind, school vouchers, PASS initiative, in-state tuition for illegal immigrants, Virginia Tech admission policies, University of Virginia parking garage, Virginia Tech's admission to the Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC), Mary Washing College name change, and proposal for a new university in the Martinsville-Henry County region.
  - 2002
    - 2000214 - 2000290 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - 2000291 - 2000566 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - 2000633 - 2000698 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - 2000699 - 2001868 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - 2001879 - 2002414 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - 2002415 - 2003017 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - 2003038 - 2003228 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - 2003233 - 2003528 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - 2003530 - 2003723 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - 2003749 - 2003976 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - 2003980 - 2004651 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - 2004655 - 2005134 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - 2005184 - 2005220 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - 2005333 - 2006900 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - 2007298 - 2007931 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - 2007988 - 2009946 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - 2010468 - 2012300 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - 2012301 - 2013964 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - 2013989 - 2014725 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - 2014778 - 2015966 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - 2016109 - 2017408 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - 2017608 - 2018786 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - 2018788 - 2019218 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - 2019220 - 2019976 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - 2020025 - 2020253 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - 2020269 - 2020966 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - 2021011 - 2022542 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - 2022543 - 2022636 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - 2023295 - 2023799 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - 2023800 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - 2023801 (part one) (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - 2023801 (part two) (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - 2023801 (part three) (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - 2023815 - 2024651 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - 2024692 - 2024765 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - 2025025 - 2025108 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - 2025109 - 2025947 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - 2025948 - 2026608 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - 2026670 - 2026989 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - 2027011 - 2027688 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - 2028173 - 2030070 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - 2030071 - 2030679 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - 2030703 - 2031332 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - 2031398 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - 2031399 - 2032201 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - 2032226 - 2032852 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - 2032856 - 2033533 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - 2033570 - 2033975 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - 2034052 - 2034943 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - 2034966 - 2035491 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - 2035547 - 2036014 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - 2036021 - 2036897 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - 2037286 - 2038508 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - 2038537 - 2039329 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - 2039337 - 2040305 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - 2040306 - 2040979 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - 2040981 - 2041277 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - 2041301 - 2043217 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - 2043374 - 2044610 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - 2045037 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - 2045133 - 2045806 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 2045807 - 2049979 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - 2050199 - 2051998 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - 2052280 - 2052940 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - 2053036 - 2053882 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - 2054013 - 2055182 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - 2055212 - 2055643 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - 2055675 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - 2055676 - 2057288 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - 2057874 - 2058374 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - 2058378 - 2059937 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - 2060066 - 2062920 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - 2062974 - 2066083 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - 2066125 - 2067842 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - 2068157 - 2070802 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - 2071086 - 2072587 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - 2072588 - 2073870 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - 2073971 - 2075355 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - 2075428 - 2076771 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - 2076818 - 2079794 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - 2003
    - 2080093 - 2080836 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - 2081394 - 2085232 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - 2085345 - 2087513 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - 2088132 - 2089995 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - 2090010 - 2092295 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - 2092345 - 2093160 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - 2093165 - 2094957 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - 2095098 - 2099784 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - 2100145 - 2102590 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - 2102797 - 2106275 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - 2106357 - 2107079 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - 2107102 - 2109898 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - 2110021 - 2112806 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - 2112906 - 2117525 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - 2117562 - 2118610 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - 2118611 - 2120349 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - 2120359 - 2121388 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - 2121507 - 2123468 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - 2123680 - 2127784 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - 2127794 - 2134325 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - 2134952 - 2140386 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - 2140735 - 2146702 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - 2146703 - 2149958 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - 2150153 - 2159804 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - 2160107 - 2161192 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - 2161194 - 2163610 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - 2163611 - 2164942 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - 2165210 - 2166066 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - 2166067 - 2167939 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - 2167950 - 2172093 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - 2172929 - 2178559 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - 2128670 - 2188662 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - 2188701 - 2190665 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - 2190762 - 2193939 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - 2194017 - 2197412 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - 2197519 - 2202334 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - 2202354 - 2205224 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - 2205300 - 2207880 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - 2207966 - 2210923 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - 2211721 - 2215898 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - 2216205 - 2218623 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - 2218639 - 2220492 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - 2220503 - 2222087 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - 2222100 - 2223579 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - 2223603 - 2224458 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - 2224462 - 2226326 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - 2226328 - 2227591 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 2227608 - 2230650 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - 2230810 - 2234135 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - 2234379 - 2242738 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - 2004
    - 2242741 - 2247587 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - 2247683 - 2253308 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - 2253792 - 2255643 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - 2255714 - 2259994 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - 2260329 - 2261861 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - 2261865 - 2266067 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - 2266245 - 2269999 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - 2270054 - 2279441 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - 2280740 - 2284121 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - 2284150 - 2289393 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - 2289394 - 2297605 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - 2297838 - 2308666 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - 2308690 - 2311413 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - 2311469 - 2319996 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - 2320003 - 2327200 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - 2327361 - 2336502 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - 2336852 - 2339963 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - 2340333 - 2344510 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - 2345006 - 23247229 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - 2347240 - 2352072 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - 2352083 - 2355583 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - 2355639 - 2358322 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - 2358339 - 2359052 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - 2359056 - 2360271 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - 2360411 - 2361253 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - 2361418 - 2362514 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - 2362515 - 2363417 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - 2363555 - 2365896 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - 2365915 - 2367804 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - 2367816 - 2369692 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - 2370159 - 2372093 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - 2372153 - 2374580 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - 2374617 - 2376445 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - 2376469 - 2378276 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - 2378314 - 2382193 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - 2382212 - 2384545 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - 2384550 - 2385733 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - 2385743 - 2391668 (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - 2005
    - 2391672 - 2395074 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - 2395097 - 2401533 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - 2401607 - 2406798 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - 2406875 - 2415064 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - 2415704 - 2422054 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - 2422105 - 2424961 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - 2424966 - 2426023 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - 2426025 - 2428560 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - 2428570 - 2431348 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - 2431365 - 2439380 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - 2440265 - 2446527 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - 2446626 - 2456703 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - 2457033 - 2464822 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - 2465108 - 2473417 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - 2473780 - 2481682 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - 2481840 - 2491194 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - 2491198 - 2495248 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - 2495775 - 2502941 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - 2502972 - 2504543 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - 2504778 - 2509250 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - 2509251 - 2513333 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - 2503794 - 2557682 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - 2557484 - 2560379 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - 2560381 - 2564133 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 2002-2005
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Copies of miscellaneous correspondence, 2002-2005 (Box 64, Folder 4)
- IV. Office of the Secretary, 2001-2006., Extent: 8.40 cubic feet (24 boxes). (Box 65-804)
  The Office of the Secretary series is housed in 24 archival boxes and is arranged into two subseries. Subseries have been designated for: A. Correspondence of Secretary Belle Wheelan (2002-2005) and Secretary Peter Blake (2005-2006), 2002-2006; and B. Files of Sarah Finley, Deputy Secretary of Education. This series documents the Office of the Secretary's response to primarily constituent correspondence. This series contains correspondence from Belle Wheelan's (2002-2005) or Peter Blake's (2005-2006) as well as the files of Deputy Secretary Sarah Finley.
  Also included are Deputy Secretary of Education Sarah Finley's files.
  - Subseries IV.A. Correspondence of Secretary Belle Wheelan (2002-2005) and Secretary Peter Blake (2005-2006), 2002-2006., Extent: 3.85 cubic feet. (Box 65-75)
    This subseries is housed in 11 boxes and is arranged chronologically. This subseries contains copies of out-going correspondence from the Secretary of Education (Belle Wheelan, 2002-2005 and Peter Blake, 2005-2006). The majority of these records are duplicated in Series III. Constituent Correspondence.
    Some of the notable correspondence in this series relates to the following topics: No Child Left Behind, Tuition Assistance Grant (TAG) program, education funding, Standards of Learning (SOL), budget cuts in state aid to public libraries, college tuition increases, teacher salaries, consolidating the Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind, school vouchers, Mary Washing College name change, and proposal for a new university in the Martinsville-Henry County region. Also included are requests for travel and approval for hiring outside consultants made by educational institutions between 2002 and 2004.
    - 15 January 2002 - 28 February 2002 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - 28 February 2002 - 5 March 2002 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - 8 March 2002 - 26 March 2002 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - 1 April 2002 - 15 April 2002 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - 16 April 2002 - 13 May 2002 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - 14 May 2002 - 31 May 2002 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 3 June 2002 - 1 July 2002 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - 1 July 2002 - 8 July 2002 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - 8 July 2002 - 31 July 2002 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - 1 August 2002 - 26 August 2002 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - 26 August 2002 - 18 September 2002 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - 20 September 2002 - 3 October 2002 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - 7 October 2002 - 11 October 2002 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - 14 October 2002 - 23 October 2002 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - 25 October 2002 - 25 November 2002 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - 25 November 2002 - 19 December 2002 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - 19 December 2002 - 13 January 2003 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - 14 January 2003 - 27 January 2003 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - 28 January 2003 - 5 February 2003 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - 6 February 2003 - 20 February 2003 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - 21 February 2003 - 5 March 2003 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - 6 March 2003 - 24 March 2003 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - 25 March 2003 - 3 April 2003 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 4 April 2003 - 24 April 2003 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 30 April 2003 - 23 May 2003 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - 27 May 2003 - 5 June 2003 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - 9 June 2003 - 24 June 2003 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - 24 June 2003 - 17 July 2003 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - 18 July 2003 - 18 August 2003 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - 18 August 2003 - 11 September 2003 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - 12 September 2003 - 9 October 2003 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - 20 October 2003 - 3 November 2003 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - 3 November 2003 - 7 November 2003 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - 10 November 2003 - 2 December 2003 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - 4 December 2003 - 13 January 2004 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - 14 January 2004 - 30 January 2004 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - 3 February 2004 - 13 February 2004 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - 16 February 2004 - 10 March 2004 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - 11 March 2004 - 14 April 2004 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - 16 April 2004 - 10 June 2004 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - 14 June 2004 - 29 July 2004 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - 2 August 2004 - 31 August 2004 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - 2 September 2004 - 26 September 2004 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - 28 September 2004 - 25 October 2004 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - 25 October 2004 - 1 November 2004 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - 1 November 2004 - 23 November 2004 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - 23 November 2004 - 29 November 2004 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - 1 December 2004 - 15 December 2004 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - 16 December 2004 - 12 January 2005 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - 13 January 2005 - 15 February 2005 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - 17 February 2005 - 17 March 2005 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - 18 March 2005 - 5 April 2005 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - 6 April 2005 - 12 May 2005 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - 18 May 2005 - 20 June 2005 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - 27 June 2005 - 19 August 2005 (Box 74, Folder 1)